jobspotting.com 2019-12-09

# Jobspotting - Job Search & Personalised Job Discovery

## Privacy Policy

Last reviewed: May 24, 2018

This is the Privacy Policy of SmartRecruiters GmbH, Winsstraße 62 / 63, 10405 Berlin, registered with the commercial registrar of the local court of Berlin Charlottenburg under HRB 153616B (hereinafter: “we”). The Privacy Policy shall apply to the use of the website [www.jobspotting.com](http://www.jobspotting.com/) and the Jobspotting App (the “Services“).

The Services provide a personalised search engine for job advertisements. The user (hereinafter: “you”) accesses aggregated job advertisements from internet job portals. These are filtered and classified according to your wishes and specifications. We show you the advertisements of other websites and services, and forward your application documents to potential employers, provided you release these through your personal account. We also show you job advertisements published on Jobspotting by our clients, and allow direct application through your user account. By checking the corresponding checkbox when creating a user account, you give us your consent for the following data collection and processing.

Because we offer you real choice and control overt how you us your Personal Data and want to build trust and engagement with you, consent is the legitimate basis for processing your Personal Data.

You can withdraw your consent at any time by deleting your user account. For more details about your rights, please refer to section 12 “Your Rights and Contact”.

We as the operator of the website are the body responsible for your Personal Data within the context of the German Data Protection Act (BDSG). Notwithstanding the foregoing, if you apply directly to any company through the Jobspotting-portal, such company will be the body responsible for the Personal Data (within the meaning of the BDSG) transferred in connection with the application.

We shall protect your privacy and private data. We collect, process and use your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy as well as the applicable German Data Protection Laws, in particular the German Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the German Telemedia Act (TMG).

#### 1\. Collecting Personal Data

Personal Data within the context of this Privacy Policy is individual information on your personal or material circumstances. These include in particular:

  * Your email address
  * The information you provide through your user account
  * Any application documents you submit to potential employers through your user account
  * Information on your usage of our services (such as the scope of data transfer, the location from which you retrieve data from our Services, as well as other connection data and sources that you retrieve). This is usually done by way of log files and cookies. For further information on log files and cookies, please see below.

#### 2\. Login Data

You can use some of our Services only if you create a user account. For this purpose, you have to choose a username and password and provide an e-mail address. This data cannot be viewed by other users. We will not pass on your data to third parties. We shall only use it in order to contact you.  
You can change your password and email address at any time.

#### 3\. Links to Social Networks

You may link your user account to your LinkedIn, XING, Facebook or Google account. Separate privacy policies apply to social networks and you will be asked to consent separately.

When you link your user account to these social networks, you agree that we may share your usernames with these respective operators. Through your user settings, you can decide whether and which content can also be viewed on these social networks.

#### 4\. Purpose of Use

We use your Personal Data for the following purposes:

  * to provide you with the Services we offer;
  * to ensure that our Services are presented in the most effective and interesting manner for you, for example by saving display preferences;
  * to inform you of changes to our Services.
  * to provide you with interesting job suggestions based on the information provided in your user account.

#### 5\. Information about your Mobile Device

Every time you access our Services, we collect the following information from your computer or your mobile device:

  * IP address,
  * the operating system you use,
  * product and version information of the browser you use,
  * your location,
  * the app or website from which you accessed our Services
  * time of access.  
In addition, upon collection of this data, we also collect the status and the volume of the data transmitted. The IP address of your computer is stored only for the duration of your usage of the website and is deleted or is shortened and thus rendered anonymous after website usage without delay. All other data is stored for a limited period. We use this data for the operation of our website, in particular in order to detect or to eliminate errors on the website, to determine the utilisation of the website and in order to make adaptations or improvements.

#### 6\. Cookies

We may also collect information on your use of our website using browser cookies. These are small text files stored on your data storage medium, which save the specific settings and data exchange with our system via your browser. A cookie typically contains the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, information on the age of the cookie and alphanumeric identifiers. Cookies help our systems to identify the user’s device and to immediately make available possible preferences. When a user accesses the platform a cookie is transmitted to the hard disk of the computer or the mobile device of the respective user. Cookies help us to improve our website and offer you a better service tailored to you. They enable us to identify your computer or mobile device when you return to our website and thus:

  * saves information on the preferred activities on the website and thus adapts our website to your individual interests. This includes for example advertising corresponding to your personal interests.
  * accelerate the handling of your requests.  
The cookies we use only save the above-mentioned data on your use of the website. There will be no reference to you personally, but a reference to an identification number pertaining to the cookie (“Cookie-ID”). The Cookie-ID is not consolidated with your name, your IP address or with similar data which would enable us to assign the cookie to you. Please see No. 7 to learn how to deactivate browser cookies.

#### 7\. Tracking and Targeting

Our Services use so-called tracking technologies. We use these technologies in order to make the web content more interesting for you. This technique makes it possible to address Internet users who have already shown interest in our website through advertisements on the websites of our partners. The advertising material is shown on the websites of our partners on the basis of a cookie technology and of an analysis of the previous user behaviour. The analysis is effected under a pseudonym and no user profiles are consolidated with your Personal Data. In case you do not consent to the compilation of user profiles, you may object by notifying us. In this case, a special opt-out cookie is transmitted to your computer or your mobile device, which has to be stored permanently. In case you delete this cookie or in case the cookie is automatically deleted due to the browser settings, you will have to reinstall this cookie when you visit our website again.

In case you do not agree to the use of browser cookies, you can change your browser settings, so that a storage of cookies will not be accepted. Please note that the website may not function properly and/or some features may not be available to you in that case. In case you would like to accept our own cookies, but not the cookies of our service providers and partners, you can choose the setting in your browser “disable third-party cookies”.  
You can deactivate Google Analytics by way of a browser add-on in case you do not agree to website analysis. You can download it here: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

In order to deactivate Google Analytics for smartphones, please click here.

#### 8\. Data Protection & Retention of your Personal Data

All information you provide to us is stored on servers within the European Union. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not absolutely secure and thus, we cannot guarantee the protection of the data transmitted to our website via the Internet. However, we secure our website and other systems through technical and organizational measures against loss, destruction, access, changes or distribution of your data by unauthorized persons. In particular, your Personal Data is transmitted in encrypted form. We use the coding system SSL (Secure Socket Layer).

We will retain your Personal Data only for as long as (i) necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and (ii) you do not withdraw your consent.

#### 9\. Transfer of Your Personal Data

We use a limited number of third-party providers in Europe and US to perform tracking services as mentioned above, technical operations and provide data hosting services. Our hosting location is the Belgian cluster of Google. Our third-party providers comply with the applicable data protection laws for transfer and processing of Personal Data and provide adequate technical and organizational measures to protect the Personal Data. We do not transfer your Personal Data to other third parties, unless you consented to such a data transfer. We will also pass on your Personal Data if we are obliged to as a result of legal regulations, statutory provisions and/or governmental or judicial order. This in particular serves the purposes of criminal prosecution, protection against threats and enforcement of intellectual property rights.

#### 10\. Data Protection and Third Party Websites

The Services may contain hyperlinks to and from third party websites. If you follow a hyperlink to visit one of these websites, please note that we do not assume any responsibility or guarantee for third party content or privacy policies. Please obtain information on the respective applicable privacy policies before you transmit Personal Data to this website.

#### 11\. Amendments to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time with effect for the future. The current version is available on the website. Please visit the website regularly and obtain information on the applicable Privacy Policy.

In the case where you have a user account, we will of course keep you informed about possible amendments to this Privacy Policy. In this case, we send a message to the email address you provided and will inform you automatically the first time you log in to one of the Services after any update of this Privacy Policy.

The notice contains the information that there is a possibility to object and states the period for such objection. If in addition further consent to the handling of your data is required, we will of course obtain such consent before the respective amendments become effective.

#### 12\. Your Rights and Contact

You can view and edit the data stored about you by us by visiting your user profile. You can withdraw your consent by deleting your user account in your account settings accessible through the top navigation.

You may also contact us at [hello@jobspotting.com](mailto:hello@jobspotting.com) for further support.

In addition, you can access your Personal Data at any time free of charge and you may request correction and/or deletion and/or blocking of such data. For this purpose and in order to obtain detailed information in this regard, please contact us at [hello@jobspotting.com](mailto:hello@jobspotting.com).

In case you have questions, comments or requests as regards the collection, processing and use of your Personal Data by us, please contact us also using the contact details indicated. If you have any specific data protection questions, please send an email to [dpo@smartrecruiters.com](mailto:dpo@smartrecruiters.com). We will respond in a timely manner. In case of unresolved privacy or data use concern, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your data protection supervisory authority.
